Saulo Moreira JUNIOR FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

- saulo.moreira@protonmail.com
- (438) 522-2522
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/moreirasaulo/
- https://github.com/moreirasaulo/
- Montreal, QC

SUMMARY

Driven, organized, detail-oriented problem solver, logical thinker and self-motivated person able to bring many years of work ethic and experience in a variety of challenging fields. Enthusiastic to collaborate with an organization where I can continuously grow as a developer and within the company.

LANGUAGES

English, French and Portuguese

EDUCATION

John Abbott College, Montreal – Internet Programming and Development	2021
The Complete 2021 Web Development Bootcamp, Udemy - Full Stack Web Development	2021
Federal University of Pernambuco, Recife (Brazil) – Bachelor in Philosophy	2010

TECHNOLOGIES

LANGUAGES: JavaScript, Java, C#, SQL, HTML, CSS, Git

JS UTILITIES AND FRAMEWORKS: jQuery, Node, NPM, Express, EJS, React.js

DATABASES: MySql (SQL), Robo 3T, Mongoose (MongoDB)

IDE: Visual Studio, NetBeans, VSCode, Eclipse CODE MANAGEMENT: GitHub, BitBucket, Sourcetree PROJECT MANAGEMENT: Agile, Jira, Trello, Scrum

PROJECTS

PERSONAL BANKING January 202'

Desktop application that allows bank clients to keep track of their bank accounts, view balance, perform transactions, view numerical and graphical spending reports, download or email proofs of transactions, monthly statements and update personal information.

TECHNOLOGIES: C#, SQL Server, Visual Studio, Entity Framework, Azure, MVC, Unit Testing

MANAGEMENT TOOLS: Trello, Scrum

 $\hbox{GIT HUB: $https://github.com/moreirasaulo/BankCRM-OnlineBanking}$

BANK MANAGEMENT SYSTEM December 2020

Desktop application designed for bank branch representatives to manage clients, accounts, perform transactions, issue receipts and generate monthly statements and reports that can be e-mailed or printed.

TECHNOLOGIES: C#, SQL Server, Visual Studio, WPF, Entity Framework

MANAGEMENT TOOLS: Trello, Scrum

 $\hbox{GIT HUB: $https://github.com/moreirasaulo/BankCRM-OnlineBanking}$

THE DOG THERAPISTS WEBSITE October 2020

Responsive website that offers training programs for pets, displays pictures and information about satisfied 'customers' and provides a form in which the user can input personal and pet's information for free assessment.

TECHNOLOGIES: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, VS Code

FRAMEWORK: Bootstrap 4.5

WEBSITE: https://www.dogtherapists.ipd23.com/

WORK EXPERIENCE

SOLUTIONS DEVELOPER August 2021 - Present

Objectif Lune Inc. - Software Company - Canada

- Develop turnkey solutions with Objectif Lune software and implement them with customers
- Determine the best implementation approaches and methods
- Provide technical and functional analyses, write and revise statements of work
- Validate the needs and requirements, and ensure regular follow-up with the various stakeholders

MANAGER June 2018 - October 2019

Optimum Inc. (10633593 Canada Inc.) - Recruitment Agency - Canada

- Selected and interviewed candidates
- Organized budget and expenses
- Planned the online platform and the recruitment system
- Responsible for the human relations between the company's partners and the subcontractors
- General administration

TECHNICAL SUPPORT AGENT

February 2018 - June 2018

CGI - IT Company - Canada

- Provided technical support to the company's clients across the globe
- Showed high listening skills and emotional intelligence

BILINGUAL CUSTOMER SERVICE REPRESENTATIVE

August 2014 - October 2017

Finastra - Finance and Technology - Canada

- Answered incoming calls (average 50/day) resolving issues with both branch representatives and end customers
- Interacted with several departments in order to manage the best way to get things done efficiently, demonstrating sense of cooperation and strong abilities as a team-worker
- Consistently scored above 85% on the quality assurance of the company, and often making top-3 with more than 90% in scorecard related to call quality
- Performed constantly among the bests of cheques department according to statistics related to efficiency, being consistently part of the top-3 stats performer of the company

HIGH SCHOOL TEACHER - Philosophy

January 2010 - January 2012

Espaço Educacional Alternativo - Education - Brazil

- Prepared own materials and texts
- Helped students individually with more difficulty to learn the main subjects
- Taught extra-curricular courses in subjects like Logic, Ethics and Aesthetics
- Encouraged students to think by themselves, with an epistemological and rational view of the world

CONTINUING EDUCATION & CERTIFICATES

Certificate in Networking - Cisco Google Apps Administrator Fundamentals - Google 2017 2015

VOLUNTEERING

FUNDRAISER - Dublin, Ireland

December 2013 - April 2014

Helped to raise funds to the Irish Heart Foundation and Red Cross

HOBBIES & INTERESTS

Technology, cinema, soccer, philosophy, poetry, science, economy, knowledge of diverse cultures